{
    "id": "ee6806f039994b1f9ad241accbc1093e",
    "title": "Subject-verb agreement quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Our team ………………… going to lose the match.",
            "description": "Collective nouns are normally used with singular verbs especially when we are talking about the group as a whole. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "A number of people ………………… tried to find the treasure.",
            "description": "We normally use plural verbs with expressions like 'a number of people' or 'most of us'.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The majority of criminals …………………. non-violent.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here."
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A lot of social problems ………………… caused by poverty.",
            "description": "If we use a plural noun after 'a lot of', the verb is also plural.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A couple of my friends ………………… going to open a travel agency.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "One of my friends ……………….. going to Venezuela.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the singular expression 'one', so we need a singular verb here. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Wasps ..................... a serious problem in our garden.",
            "description": "The noun 'wasps' is plural and hence it requires a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A good knowledge of three languages ..................... necessary for this job.",
            "description": "Here the subject is the singular expression 'a good knowledge'.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The police ……………….. looking for a balding man in his forties.",
            "description": "The noun 'police' is always used with plural verbs.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Many cattle ……………….. died because of the drought.",
            "description": "The noun cattle is plural and hence it requires a plural verb.",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}